how to edit how to edit your code your
notes your markdown your HTML your CSS
your JavaScript even your python but
more particularly how do you edit the
stuff that you're going to make for your
website okay so up to now we have been
using GitHub we've been using uh the
GitHub tool here and we have been
clicking on
raw and and not raw but we've clicking
on
edit and we've been going here to just
use the inplace editor and this is fine
there's absolutely nothing wrong with
using the the in placeplace editor and
clicking on Commit right and for a tiny
little change that's probably going to
be the thing to do but what about when
you need to do something more serious
okay so this is the beginning of using a
graphical user interface editor and some
of you may have already discovered if
you click over here and you go to open
with GitHub Dev that other words dot by
the way that means you can push a period
let's try that if you click if you tap
period on any text any document at all
you tap period it will open it in this
really crazy awesome editor which for
many of you will be the first time
seeing it and for others of you like oh
my gosh I know what that is that's vs
code spoiler alert it absolutely is and
we are ALS also going to talk about that
later so as you can see you can go in
here and you can see the different
things about it it's showing you the
readmes and stuff like that but this is
really not what we wanted this is like a
fullblown editor if you click on the
outline here you can see that it didn't
actually open the thing that we wanted
it to but if you go back let's let's
let's see if we can go back here and
let's do this one let's say open with
get up Dev it actually should do it why
didn't it do it the last time okay there
we go so there I guess it must have been
because it was the first
time uh but now you can see here's the
same files that we had before and
there's Elliot and all of that you can
even see the picture uh it'll show us
the pictures and you can go in here and
you get this nice pretty thing in fact
there's some other things too here and
so we did markdown last time but here's
something really good lot of people ask
last time how do I preview well there's
a little button right here open preview
to the side split editor so you can
click on open preview and now you can
edit your notes and see your notes right
next to it a lot of people were
suggesting places to do markdown editing
on different websites out there and I
was kind of putting them off because
this is what I I knew I was going to go
with this eventually um because this is
by far the easiest way to preview your
notes this is integrated into GitHub
already um you can actually test things
um you know you could say uh um you know
uh I don't know I think it's green for
Ben so you see what I'm saying you get
to see live edits now for the for many
of you you may have already discovered
that um and what I don't I mean I don't
remember uh a bunch of things about this
like I like for example okay look so I
obviously I have something to change
here so you can click on this source
code oh he remember that commit and push
button there it is we click on Commit
and push you must specify a comment uh
added uh Ben colors and then this is
different though it makes you put a
comment see before you didn't have to do
that before but that's a good thing my
friends because now you're going to
start to see commit history and stuff we
don't know anything about G at this
point and you don't need to all you need
to take away from this is that you have
now got an editor and you can see things
in fact if you make a change to
something uh it will tell you see over
here see the little X right there that
means that um oh actually that's
different it should automatic this does
not have Auto sa I'm confusing it with
something else so this does say that you
have you have some changes queued up
that need to be made um and actually it
does show you what has changed though
that little green there that's the stuff
that hasn't been saved yet okay so or
committed in this case let's use the
proper terminology it hasn't been
committed yet right
so so that is it that is how you go
about editing things um in kind of a
better way um and it's an easier way and
it does have some other advantages so
we're not going to go into all of the
different things you can do with that
we're actually going to talk about that
in the next video but I wanted to make
you aware of what we'll use let's use
the official terminology
into the system and you can still you
know use the previewing over here you
can use preview and then change the code
here uh or you can use the new fancy
version over here uh
github.com doing that I do recommend
however that you go over here and
practice uh messing with your notes oh
God look at all these splits I just made
I don't need that many splits let's go
here let's do this and a preview okay so
that is all that is all for this video
uh watch for other videos about ways to
do this without necessarily using GitHub
we'll talk about those next